レベルの高いサバイバルバトルが 繰り広げられるようになる 「フロアマスター」への挑戦権を懸けた 試合へと変わり ２００階クラスからは この闘技場の最高位 ここは　戦いを望む者にとって 最高の舞台なのだ １００階クラスからは 専用の個室が与えられる 高さ９９１ｍを誇る　この建物は その階層に見合った報酬が 得られ 試合に勝てば 上の階へとクラスが上がり 格闘家の聖地である
Lead all the soldiers here on a mission
「念」の使い手から 身を守る方法は一つだけ
Hey, what's that?
でないと…。
M-M-Monsters!
あ…。 あ…。 肉体は粉々に壊されてしまいます。
Target the fully grown ones.
They will provide the most nutrition. Now go!
しかし　現在では　この能力を 使いこなせる者は　ごくわずか。
A Chimera Ant queen
それ故　彼らは 天才　支配者　超能力者
moves repeatedly until she
finds a place she likes.
仙人　超人などと呼ばれ 特別視される。
As she does, she births more and more
soldier ants to build her own army.
誰もが持っている力…。 そう そして　この眠れる力を 目覚めさせる方法は２つ。
Once she's chosen a location, she births a large number of carpenter ants,
which construct her castle with incredible speed.
ゆっくり起こすか 無理やり起こすか…。 ちなみにズシは ゆっくり起こしました。
From then on, the queen remains
within the castle until death.
彼は　のみ込みが早く 努力を惜しまなかったので
So if a Queen grew to two meters tall
すごいスピードで 「纏」をマスターしました。 約半年です。 それじゃあ　ダメだ！ 俺達は０時までに「纏」を覚えて
and were to set her sights on humans, there should be entire villages
or towns of missing people.
ヒソカの「念」の壁を 突破したいんだ！
I don't see anything...
それなら 無理やり起こすしかない…。 それなら間に合うんだな？
I just checked the past six months, and the largest group only numbered ten.
君達次第ですよ。
Say, can we look up missing people individually?
時間内に　オーラを 体内に　とどめるコツを
Don't be ridiculous.
会得できるかどうか…。
You know how many hundreds of thousands
of people go missing worldwide?
そこに 懸かっているわけですからね。 これから　君達に 私のオーラを送ります。
We should be able to see which areas
have the highest concentrations.
「発」と呼ばれる さっきみたいなやつです。 あ…。 あ…。
No good... The data's two years old.
もちろん　君達の体を壊すのが 目的ではないから
Perhaps we should start by checking for sightings. If someone saw a two-meter insect,
they'd make a big fuss.
手加減は　するが…。
We tried that, of course.
荒っぽい方法であることに 変わりない。
But we couldn't find anything.
要するに　ビックリさせて 目覚めさせるわけですからね。
Maybe we're getting worked up over nothing... Yeah.
眠っている体に活を入れて 「纏」を起こしやすい状態にする。
Bring up the tidal data from
the day the arm was found.
「眠っている」とは 体内にある　精孔という穴が 閉じきっていて
The arm was discovered here...
オーラが うまく巡っていない状態のこと。
Now go back ten days.
そこで　私のオーラを 君達の体内に一気に送ることで 精孔をこじ開けます。
Locate any currents that may have carried
the arm to that location in that time. What do you mean?
本来なら　瞑想や禅などで 自分のオーラを感じ取り
was severed after the Chimera Ant made landfall. That makes sense.
体内をオーラが包んでいることを 実感した上で
It could have come from any of the Balsa Islands...
少しずつ開くものだから 時間が　かかります。
Including the Mitene Union.
天性の才能を持つ　ズシでさえ ３か月　必要としました。
The Mitene Union... Oh, where the NGL Autonomous Region is.
しかし　君達なら１週間
Yes, as well as East Gorteau.
あるいは　もっと早く 目覚めるかもしれない。
There's no getting information
out of those two countries. What's this NGL?
それだけに　残念です。
An acronym, standing for Neo-Green Life.
不本意な方法しかとれない この状況がね。 よく分かんないな。
It's a country founded by people who wanted to
live in nature, away from machine civilization.
無理やりでも より早く目覚めるほうが
Here.
いいに決まってんじゃん。 これは「外法」と呼ばれる 裏ワザですよ？ 正しい順序を踏んでいない。
Mitene Union:
NGL Autonomous Region
Republic of Rokario
Hass Republic
Republic of West Gorteau
Republic of East Gorteau They primarily communicate by letter. Primary means of transportation is by horse. Anyone knowingly bringing technology into
the country is subject to execution.
未熟な者　悪意のある者が行えば 死ぬことだってある。
In '87, a three-man TV crew was caught trying
to enter the country to get a story.
だけど　ウイングさんは 未熟でもないし　悪意もない。
One was executed, and the
other two remain in prison.
でしょ？ はぁ…。 だから　聞きたいな。
Of its 2.17 million population,
99% belong to the Neo-Green Life Party, with the rest being support volunteers.
なぜ急に　俺達に本当の四大行を 教える気になったのかさ。 惜しいと思ったのですよ。
If the Chimera Ant washed ashore there, how would the NGL citizenry react?
２００階クラスに行けば 必ず痛い目に遭う。
They probably wouldn't do anything.
あのクラスにいるのは 全員「念」の使い手ですからね。 そして「念」を知らない者が 上がって来ると
When a deadly epidemic spread throughout
the area, they let nature run its course, refusing to admit international doctors.
必ず洗礼します。 すなわち　「念」による攻撃。
And even if they tried to contact the outside,
it would be too late by the time word arrived.
つまり　私が　これから行う方法を さらに荒っぽくやるのです。 「別に　死んでも構わない」 というつもりで。
If that arm belonged to the Chimera Ant queen, she may have already begun to build her nest.
選ばれた者として。
Let's see who can bring the Queen more humans.
しかし　その代償は大きい…。
I challenge you! Hmph.
だから　先に 知っておいてほしかった。
What? You're running away? Hey, accept my challenge!
いろいろと　もったいつけて 脅かしもしましたが
Accept?
君達なら　この方法で 確実に目覚めるでしょう。
Are you issuing an order?
それだけの素質がある　資格も！
Why should I follow an order from you?
荷物を下ろして　上着は脱いで
I can only follow the Queen's orders.
背中を　こちらへ向けてください。
You're just scared of losing. My squadron is comprised of elite soldiers.
すごく熱い… それに　ウイングさんは 触ってないのに
I should get the other squadron leaders in on this. If we all compete, we'll capture more prey. More prey?
グンと押されている気がする
I see...
これだ　この感じ…
I agree with that idea.
見えない　ぶよぶよが 皮一枚　隔てた所で
If we gather more prey, the Queen will be pleased.
まとわりついてるような…
Okay, that settles it.
この肌触りを 何億倍も嫌な感じにすると
However, I believe that the
prey's quality also matters.
兄貴の「念」になるのか 行きますよ。
We must ensure that the Queen
eats highly nutritious humans. That guy's such a stiff...
うわ！
That's what makes him endearing. He is dedicated and loyal.
うっ　うわ！ 今　全身の精孔は開かれました。
I presume the human he was created
from was also quite earnest.
このままの勢いで出し続ければ 当然　疲れます。
Hey, wait! Weren't you supposed to get some rest?
いったんオーラを出し尽くせば 全身疲労で立てませんよ。
I'll bring her back. Don't bother, it won't help.
やっぱり？ いいですか　オーラを体に とどめようと念じながら
But she goes to the forest every morning, and she spends the whole day searching.
構えてください　目を閉じて！
Right, she'll probably collapse soon...
どんな形でもいいです 自分のイメージしやすい構えで
But she can't stop looking. That's what it means to be a parent.
そして　オーラが血液のように 全身を巡っているよう 想像してください。
How many days has it been since
Kurt-kun and Reina-chan vanished?
頭の　てっぺんから　右の肩　手
It's like spirits whisked them away.
そして　その流れが 次第に　ゆっくり止まり
Big bugs... Huh?
思い浮かべるのです。
We haven't raided this area yet.
どんな感じですか？
Mom!
何か　緩い粘液の中にいるみたい。
It must be them...
うん　重さのない服を 着てるみたいだ。
Those monsters must have stolen your children!
さっきまでの君達なら
This should suffice to please the Queen.
よく分かった。
Wh-What's happening?
私の放つ「念」を 無事　防ぐことができれば
Exterminate the insects quickly.
彼の壁も破れるでしょう！
That's Gyro's order.
では　行きます！
Gyro? What's that? Our king's name!
ふん。
take an airship to the neighboring
Republic of Rokario, and travel by land from there. It "ant" gonna be easy to get into
a country of such nasty rumors.
フッ。
It's derived from the bila tree,
native to the Mitene Union.
洗礼は受けずに済みそうだね。
So the nasty rumors are saying that the
drug is being manufactured in NGL?
君が天空闘技場に来た 理由は　想像できる。
They're only rumors. No one has been able to publicly prove it.
ここで鍛えてから 僕と戦うつもりだったんだろ？ ああ　けど　そっちから現れると 思わなかったよ。
After all, the country's locked down tight. When people try to get in to
investigate, they're executed. Executed...
手間が省けた。
He wasn't executed?
フッフッフ…。 「纏」を覚えたくらいで いい気になるなよ。 「念」は奥が深い。
No, if he'd been captured trying
to uncover NGL's secrets, he'd have probably been executed
like that TV crewman.
はっきり言って　今の君と戦う気は 全くない。
But this reporter was wearing a wire, from which we intercepted the final message.
だが…。
When the message was played... M-Monsters...
このクラスで 一度でも勝つことができたら
Giant bugs!
相手になろう。
Giant bugs?
行こう。
That isn't enough information to be sure...
新入り？ みたいだ　ね。
Then that settles it.
フッフッフ。
I'll get three tickets. Make it four.
そうだ　ね。
I'm coming with you. You can't.
２００階クラスへ　ようこそ！ こちらに登録の署名を お願いします。
You aren't allowed to bring technology into NGL. If they discover you with cell phones
or wireless communicators, you'll be arrested right away.
早速　参戦の申し込みも なさいますか？
So if there's any trouble, you'll need me...
このクラスは 申告戦闘制といいまして
Or rather, you'll need them.
その間であれば　戦いたい日に 戦っていただけるシステムです。
They can carry a letter anywhere.
もちろん　毎日 戦ってもらっても結構ですし
I get it.
期間内ギリギリまで戦わなくても 問題ありません。
They'll certainly come in handy.
登録が抹消されてしまいますので ご注意ください。 一度　戦えばってことは このクラスは　何回も戦うの？
It may be a bit late to ask, but are you sure you want to come? Of course!
はい　このクラスをクリアするには １０勝が必要となります。 しかし　１０勝する前に ４敗してしまいますと
You weren't kidding about the "late" part. We have no idea what the situation is inside NGL.
これまた失格となってしまいます。 そして！
There may very well be a swarm
of giant Chimera Ants already, hunting humans down.
晴れて１０勝しますと　なんと フロアマスターに挑戦することが できるんです！
If that turns out to be the case, my priority will be saving them.
フロアマスターとは　２１名の 最高クラスの選手達のこと。
So I may not be able to help you. You must be able to protect yourselves.
２３０階から２５０階までの 各フロアを
If you want to come, that's the requirement.
それぞれ　たった１人の選手が 占有しています。
Okay, got it. We'll be fine.
もう　お分かりですね？ フロアマスターに挑戦して勝てば その瞬間から　あなたが　その階の マスターとなれるのです！
And if I'm the one who's in danger, you should escape without me.
それだけではありません フロアマスターになれば　なんと！
Got it?
そんなことよりさ 最上階には　他に何かないの？
A pretty good haul.
「そんなこと」？ その大会で優勝すれば
But it's not even half the size of
what my squadron delivered...
最上階が　優勝者の家になるのよ！ とっても名誉なことなの。
My focus was quality. And I wasn't competing against you.
高さ　約１０００ｍのペントハウスよ!? 分かってるの？
Whatever. Anyway, did you hear?
でも　確か　キルアん家は 標高３７００ｍだったよね。
That turtle guy ran into human resistance. Resistance?
うっ…。 そ…　それに 副賞として毎回　超希少な…。
Hmm, those were probably guns. Guns?
どうする？　ゴン。 俺　最上階の秘密　分かったから
Put simply, it's a barrel that launches
metal projectiles called bullets
もういいや。 うぅ…。
using the explosive force of gunpowder.
うん　俺もヒソカと戦えれば それでいいや！
It's one of the most commonly
used human weapons.
あんた達　何しに来たのよ！
No idea what you're talking about... If you want the details, read books.
じゃあ　お前は　ここで １勝しなきゃな。 でも　すぐには参加しないんだろ？ ううん…。
Books are wonderful. You can learn about how these
human creatures think, behave, and function as a society.
やる！
Can you answer my question, then?
やってみなきゃ　今までの相手と どれだけ違うか　分かんないしね。
Do humans have armies too? Armies? Yes, that was an army.
じゃあ　こちらの申し込み用紙にも 書いておいてね。 はい！
They belong to a military body
led by an authoritative figure, much like ourselves!
何か用？ いいや　別に。
Ah, I have another question. They mentioned something about a name.
俺達も申し込みをしたいから 並んでいるだけ　ね。
A name? I can't blame you for not understanding.
フッフッフ…。
Because it's a human idea
we do not make use of.
ヘッヘッへ…。
Put simply...
なるほどね。
So it seems there are humans
ゴン　こいつら お前と同じ日に戦いたいらしいぜ。
capable of more than running and crying.
フッフッフ。
I don't know why that should surprise you.
俺　いつでもＯＫです！
After all, their blood flows through us.
元気のいい坊やだ　ね。 フッフッフ。
Assemble, squadron leaders!
それでは　ゴン様は２２０７号室
キルア様は２２２３号室で お休みください。
The Queen summons us. Assemble, squadron leaders!
戦闘日は 決定次第　お知らせします。 ありがとう！
Do you get a headache when
the Queen calls to us? Yeah, my ears start ringing.
あいつらが メガネにいさんが言ってた 「洗礼を受けた連中」なんだろうな。
I shall now begin preparations
for the King's birth.
何も知らずに来てたら 俺達も　ああなってたってことか。
Every day, provide me with fifty humans.
うわ！　広いね！
Yes, Majesty!
おい！　聞いてんのか？ ピッカピカの　お風呂だよ！
Your Majesty, may I ask a question?
うわ こんなデッカいベッド　初めて！
Permitted. Speak.
見て　キルア！ [TV] おい！　ゴン！ ん？
Among the humans are soldiers like ourselves, with weapons to use against us. We must fortify our defenses, in preparation for any potential attack.
えっ　明日？　早っ！
I have a few ideas...
Would you care to hear them?
多分　明日は勝てない。 でも　いいんだ。
I must focus entirely on my son. Yes, and one more thing...
早く実感してみたいんだ。
Would you allow us to have names?
この力で　一体 どんなことができるのか。
What is a name? It's like a code that can be
used to identify each of us.
さぁ　今日は大注目の一戦です！ まずは　破竹の勢いで 勝ち上がってまいりました
How peculiar.
ゴン選手が　早くも登場です！
They speak their minds and
request to use these names.
対します　ギド選手は ここまで　５戦して ４勝１敗と まずまずの成績を残しています。
While bettering the race, they compete for glory, leading to a stronger sense of individuality.
フッフッフ…。 ((いいですか ゴンくん　キルアくん))
Regardless, I feel quite confident now.
((「纏」は　あくまでも 防御が主体で 攻撃力が上がるわけでは ありません))
I can see you already, as though
recalling a memory from my past.
((それに 防御力が上がるといっても
My King...
殴られれば痛いし　ケガもします)) ((相手が　はるかに強い 「念」の使い手ならば
You shall stand atop this world!
((ですから　戦うのは ２か月　我慢してください)) ((その間に　できる限りのことは 教えましょう))
Names... Quite amusing. The King's three Royal Guards.
ごめんなさい　ウイングさん どうしても　今 戦ってみたいんだ！
I shall name you myself.
やれやれ　困った子だなぁ。
Remember what Kite said before we left? That we should escape without
him if he's in danger.
それでは　始め！
Yeah, I don't think it was a choice...
ハア!! ハッハッハ…。
That's why neither of us said anything, but I've been thinking. Is it possible for Kite, who earned Ging's respect, to be in that much danger?
出ました！ ギド選手の「舞闘独楽」！ 多数の独楽を自在に操り 敵を攻撃するという
You said that Ging had a reason for
bringing Kite and me together... Yeah.
彼独特のスタイルです！
You're probably right.
行くぜ！ 「戦闘円舞曲」！
I don't know the reason, but I can't give up halfway,
no matter what's going on.
グワっ…！
So I won't run away. That's what I've decided.
クリーンヒット！ おっと　ゴン選手 いきなり　クリーンヒット！
Man, you had this totally serious expression, so I was expecting something big.
１ポイントを奪われました！
But it's just business as usual. Huh? I thought about this a lot.
これは厳しいスタートです！ クソ！
I even ran a bunch of mental simulations...
「念」を込められた独楽は 何時間でも回り続け
Think all you want, but you'll still be Gon.
お前を襲う！ 複雑に舞い飛ぶ独楽の動きは もはや　俺でも予測不能！
If someone said you should abandon them, you'd never do it. You make it sound like I wasted
my time considering it.
ぶつかり合った独楽が 飛んで来て
Then what about you?
攻撃して来るなんて… あんな小さな独楽なのに
I'm a spontaneous guy, so I'd think
about it when the time comes.
ハンマーで ぶん殴られたみたいだ！
You mean you might run away? Depends.
「念」の使い手ばかりが集まる
I can't say until it actually happens.
２００階クラスでの 初のバトルは
Say for instance...
ゴンが想像をも していないものだった
I can't tell you what I'd do in
a hypothetical situation. I don't decide until it's time.
このピンチをゴンは 切り抜けることができるのか それとも…
The airship carrying the group
heads for the Mitene Union, still unaware of the cruel fate
that lies in wait for them...